SOFTWARE ENGINEER

LinkedIn Christopher Sorge



Central Pennsylvania

PROFILE

Mr. Sorge has more than 17 years of experience in customer service, management, finance, business analysis, procurement, and information assurance. He has worked extensively with subjects surrounding I.T. and change management for both the public and private sector. He is now focused on software development and programming in an Agile manner. He is experienced in C#, Java, JavaScript, ASP.Net MVC, SQL, HTML, and CSS. He has training in DevOps, ServiceNow, SCRUM, and QA/QC.

AREAS OF EXPERTISE

- Programming
- Procurement
- Project Management
- Change Management
- Information Assurance
- Data Analysis
- Financial Analysis
- Customer Service

EDUCATION

Diploma, TrueCoders

TrueCoders BootCamp Birmingham, AL

B.S., Public Administration

Shippensburg University Shippensburg, PA

A.A., Communications

Harrisburg Area Community College Harrisburg, PA

CERTIFICATIONS

- Certified Ethical Hacker (2018)
- Certified Penetration Tester (2018)
- ITIL v. 3 Foundations (2018)
- CNSS 4011 (2018)

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Pennsylvania Department of Human Services (Bronner Group) (2018 - 2020)

- Successfully completed a Coding Bootcamp with TrueCoders.
- Completed the SAFE Advanced Scrum Master course.
- Completed the ServiceNow Administration course.
- Conducted an assessment of the procurement function including current IT systems.
- Provided assistance by writing over 64 procurement policies and procedures.
- Developed strategic guidance utilizing Agile methodologies in SharePoint and JIRA to manage the creation of new policies, procedures, systems, and attachments.
- Served as the lead systems administrator, data analyst, business analyst, and junior project manager.

Pennsylvania Office of Administration (Adept Consulting) (2018)

- Served as a Telecommunications Project Manager for the client. Assisted in the setup and creation of an enterprise help desk for the Commonwealth of Pennsylvania.
- Obtained the ITIL Foundations certification.

Defense Logistics Agency (AR Services) (2016)

- Ensured IT asset database was updated accurately through our inventory management system (BMC Remedy) that resulted in a 20% decrease in downtime.
- Identified repetitive processing errors and helped to resolve issues/problems in supply system work processes while presenting these issues for Government approval.
- Performed causative research for inventory adjustments, location surveys, and coordination of resources with multiple stakeholders.
- Developed enterprise solutions involving SWID implementation IAW (In accordance with) ISO/IEC 19770-2:2009 for stakeholders that resulted in the development of a new program.
- Responsible for Software Asset Management at over 26 different sites both domestic and foreign.
- Appointed as the licensing manager of IBM, Adobe, and 12 other vendors.

U.S. Army National Guard (Finance Officer) (2010 - 2020)

- Prepared technical briefs and presentations for senior personnel.
- Managed 25 personnel in dynamic environments.
- Developed training curriculum for personnel.
- Managed the Information Assurance program for my unit as the appointed Information Assurance Security Officer (IT Security Training).
- Managed the Anti-Terrorism program for my unit as the appointed Anti-Terrorism Officer (Physical Security Training).
- Managed the Master Resiliency program for my unit as the appointed Master Resilience Trainer (Psychological Resiliency Training).
- Managed the Army Substance Abuse program for my unit as the appointed Unit Prevention Leader.
- Appointed Executive Officer (XO) for my unit responsible for inventory management, quality controls, and overall readiness of equipment.
- Conducted financial management operations in a variety of environments.
- Obtained the Certified Ethical Hacking and Certified Penetration Tester designations.
- Obtained CNSS 4011 Certification (Information Systems Security Certified Professional).
- Prior enlisted experience in the Army Reserves.

Banking Industry (Relationship Management / Internal Training) (2007 – 2015)

- Outside / Inside Sales Experience exceeded sales quotas on a regular basis.
- Corporate Training experience trained personnel on a regular basis.
- SME in Fiserv, Metavante, Genesis, Sales Force, and Siebel.